audience in, like using a prop or an intriguing question.
But in a one minute speech, we don't really need to do that.
The idea of having a strong introduction for longer speeches is simply because the audience's
attention is at its peak at that period.
So the more curious we can make them, the higher chance we have them of getting engaged
through the rest of our speech.
But in a 60 second speech, we don't have so much time.
Plus, because of the short length of the speech, audience just has much less time to actually
zone out.
So getting to the point would be the best way to begin.
And you can use the P3F framework.
It stands for point, past, present, and future.
For example, if you were asked to give a one minute speech on your thoughts on any issue,
let's say your thoughts on an issue like climate change, start off by simply saying,
I believe that climate change is a really pressing problem in today's world.
Directly starting off with your main point.
Let me talk a little bit about the history of climate change.
Evidence has found that traces of global warming go all the way back to the 1900s.
Our footprints can be seen because of the droughts and floods that were formed back in that period.
Let me focus on the present.
Currently, climate change has taken a very dark dawn.
The global temperatures are rising, the ice sheets are melting, and the oceans are getting warmer
because of the rapid technological innovations and massive population growth.
We're not being able to see how badly we are really affecting the Earth.
Finally, we move on to the future.
If we continue down this path and do not change the way we approach global warming and climate change,
and to take a real effort to reduce the harmful effects on Earth,
we might be digging the grave of our own species.
And that's how it can be done.
Forget the content of the speech.
It doesn't matter if you agree with it or not.
It simply gives you a framework for one minute speeches.
I know I didn't exactly speak for one minute,
but the point is that on any of the parts of past, present, or future,
you can expand upon them as much as you like.
Just remember, start with your main point, move on to the rest of your speech.
One mistake that we see a lot of people make is that when they go to deliver their one-minute speech,
they start off with,
Good morning, my name is Hardeep, and I'm here to talk to you about climate change.
Keep in mind that that's only important to do if you haven't been introduced already.
A lot of people, after getting introduced,
their name and the topic they're speaking on has been said,
they come on stage and they'll repeat that, which is not really required.
So bear in mind if you're introduced or not introduced,
and start your speech accordingly by directly jumping into the point.
If you want to go deeper and understand more frameworks about one-minute speeches that we've delivered,
you can check out an in-depth video we've made on that topic right here.